RG 004:108, Oxford Probate Court
Connecticut State Library
Oxford Probate Court records
1846-1981
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Probate Court (Oxford District)
11.5 cubic feet
Record books, 1847-1981; Probate files, 1846-1908.
RG004_108
1911-007 and 2012-025
Historical Note
Oxford, New Haven County, Town established in October 1798, Parent Towns: Derby and Southbury
The Oxford Probate District was constituted June 4, 1846, from the New Haven Probate District. The Oxford Probate District merged with the Roxbury, Southbury, and Washington, and Woodbury Probate Districts on January 5, 2011 to create the Region # 22 Probate District which serves the municipalities of Bethlehem, Oxford, Roxbury, Southbury, Washington, Watertown, and Woodbury.
Town of Oxford, Probate District chronology:
October 1798 - June 3, 1846, New Haven District
June 4, 1846 - January 4, 2011, Oxford District
January 5, 2011 - Present, Region # 22 District
For Probate Court contact information and hours of operation see,.
Scope and Content
Probate record books, Volumes 1-12, 1847-1981. Contact the probate court to access original record books after Volume 12. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Probate files, 1846-1908. Probate files may consist of estates, conservatorships, guardianships, commitments, and insolvencies. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Inventory control book, 1846-1908 (coverage). Also known as the Godard Digest, it is a list of probate files transferred to the Connecticut State Library. It was compiled at the Connecticut State Library under the direction of State Librarian George S. Godard.
Arrangement
Record books are numbered from 1 to 12. There is also a bond volume numbered 2.
Probate files in accession 1911-007 are arranged alphabetically.
Other Finding Aid
Record Books: Index cards for the record books have been scanned. Ask History and Genealogy staff for assistance. See Alternate Form Available section for volumes available on microfilm.
Probate Files: The Probate Estate Papers Index, located in the index corridor adjacent to the History and Genealogy Reading Room, has two parts, a general index covering most of the state, and a Hartford Probate District index covering Hartford and some surrounding towns, 1820-1920. The index cards are arranged alphabetically by individual's last name and first names. The cards have the individual's name, town of residence, probate district, and list of items contained in the estate packet. To request retrieval of an estate packet, copy at least the estate name, file date, and probate district name from the index card. The probate files in Accession 1911-007 are represented in this index.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Probate records -- Connecticut -- Oxford
Places:
Oxford (Conn.)
Restrictions on Access
Researchers should first consult use copies when available. See Alternate Form Available Section below.
Accession 2012-025, Record books, 1847-1981, are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Alternative Form Available
Record books, volumes 1, 2, 4, 5, 7, 8, 9, 1842-1917, probate files, 1853-1880; and inventory control book (Godard Digest) were microfilmed by the Genealogical Society of Utah and are available for use in the History and Genealogy reading room or through the.
Provenance
The probate files in accession 1911-007 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on the following dates (with date span of files): December 20, 1911 (1846-1908).
The record books in accession 2012-025 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on March 12, 2012.
Container List
- Record books, 1847-1981; 7.5 cubic feet (13 volumes); 2012-025
  - Records, 1847-1866 (Volume 1)
  - Records, 1854-1869 (Volume 2)
  - Orders and decrees, 1862-1882 (Volume 3)
    On spine: "Records"
  - Records, 1860-1872 (Volume 4)
  - Records, 1879-1883 (Volume 5)
  - Orders and decrees, 1882-1911 (Volume 6)
  - Records, 1890-1897 (Volume 7)
  - Records, 1900-1910 (Volume 8)
    On spine: "Manuscript"
  - Records, 1910-1917; On spine: "Manuscript" (Volume 9)
  - Orders and decrees, 1910-1942 (Volume 10)
  - Records, 1917-1929 (Volume 11)
  - Bonds, 1881-1962 (Volume 12)
  - Bonds, 1962-1981 (Volume 2)
- Probate files, 1846-1908; 4 cubic feet; 1911-007
  - Abbott - Fenn (Drawer 1)
  - Flagg - Perry, G. (Drawer 2)
  - Perry, H. - Sutton (Drawer 3)
  - Talmadge - Z; Miscellaneous (Drawer 4)
- Inventory Control Book, 1846-1908; T003073
  Index of probate files in accession 1911-007
  Date span is coverage
  Also known as the Godard Digest